<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on apiercey.github.io</title><link>/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on apiercey.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RygelDB</title><link>/projects/rygel-db/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/rygel-db/</guid><description>RygelDB RygelDB is a NoSQL document store using commands to store and query documents!
What the Yotz?! - Dominar Rygel the XVI
Usage Run go run . or go build ., as you like.
$ go run . Starting tcp server on localhost:8080 You can connect using a socket once it has started like so:
nc localhost 8080 Storing and Querying Data Rygel is collection based and uses commands to store and query data.</description></item><item><title>Zardoz</title><link>/projects/zardoz/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/zardoz/</guid><description>ZARDOZ A Golang testing framework for testing asyncronous dependencies.
Table of Contents Installation Usage Test Assertions t.Assert t.AssertSync t.AssertAsync Working Example Reading results Setup and Cleanup Installation Pull the module into your GOPATH using
go get github.com/apiercey/zardoz Usage ZARDOZ can be imported like so:
import z &amp;#34;github.com/APiercey/zardoz&amp;#34; ZARDOZ comes with three assertions for testing asyncronous dependencies. Test blocks begin with a Describe block, which provides a test suite.</description></item><item><title>SocialTeach</title><link>/projects/social-teach/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/social-teach/</guid><description>Proving Gamification as a Service During my time at Passion.io, we wanted to prove we Gamification as a Service was firstly possible, and secondaly scalable.
If succesful, there was a desire to integrate such a tool into our own product line. From this, SocialTeach was born and registered as a subsidiary, where I was required to lead the technical vision of the system.
After succesfully pitching the idea of, &amp;ldquo;Building a platform that learns as you interact with it and provides gamified content in any given content-based system&amp;rdquo;, at the Quality and Usability Lab of the Technical Universtity of Berlin, we began development of the system with a brilliant group of students.</description></item></channel></rss>