<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology Visionary on apiercey.github.io</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Technology Visionary on apiercey.github.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Commanded + Flow to Create a Fault-Tolerant System</title><link>/articles/elixir-meetup-num-63-create-fault-tolarent-system/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/elixir-meetup-num-63-create-fault-tolarent-system/</guid><description>Meetup Talk @ Solarisbank for Elixir Meetup #63 For Elixir Meetup #63 I presented how fault-tolarent can be built using Commanded + Flow. We had a great turn out with Solarisbank hosting.</description></item><item><title>SolarisBank Diversity Sponsor at ElixirConf Europe 2019</title><link>/articles/solarisbank-elixir-conf-2019-diversity-sponsor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/articles/solarisbank-elixir-conf-2019-diversity-sponsor/</guid><description>Diversity Sponsor Solarisbank was a Diversity Sponsor for ElixirConf Europe 2019 and I had the great opportunity to join some of my colleagues to host a small table and part-take in the talks!
Visit our Diversity sponsor @solarisBank at #ElixirConfEU and learn about their banking API, they are hiring for diversity with or without Elixir experience! pic.twitter.com/8CQuZANL9a
&amp;mdash; ElixirConf Europe (@ElixirConfEU) April 9, 2019</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/about/</guid><description>Who am I? I am Alexander Butt-Piercey, a Software Engineer and Technical Leader. I have had the pleasure to be a member of award-winning applied research teams, help build succesful startups - some reaching unicorn status, lead development in NFPs, and mentor younger professionals into blossoming careers. At the moment, I work in an incredible team at Solarisbank shipping innovative software in the digital banking space.
My interests in Software Development is in Lean Practicies, Domain Driven Design, Technical Leadership, and Continous Delivery.</description></item></channel></rss>